# Gleb Polushkin

- <sup>♠</sup> Moscow, Russia
- +7(905)755-1751
- https://github.com/proll/
- http://prolll.com

#### **SUMMARY**

9+ years of professional experience in web development. I'm a passionate and self-motivated front-end developer and I pay a lot attention to latest Javascript and browsers trends as SPA, Virtual DOM and continuous. Not only concentrating on the technical part of the job, but also on the process and reaching the project's goals.

Beloved conceptions: HTML5 and its gorgeous APIs, CSS3, LESS/Stylus, Vanilla JavaScript, Bootstrap, jQuery, BackboneJS, React, Git, Grunt, NodeJS, W3C, progressive enhancement, mobile browser optimisation and continuous integration technics.

## **SKILLS**

- JavaScript
- React
- jQuery Mobile
- HTML5
- LESS
- SASS
- Web Applications
- Web Standards
- AGAL
- Handlebars
- LMDJSON
- Front-end

- Backbone.js
- jQuery
- Node.js
- CSS
- Stylus
- SVG
- MySQL
- PHP
- Freemarker
- AMD
- Git
- XML

## **EXPERIENCE**

## iMobilco

05 / 2014 - Present

Senior Front-end developer

iMobilco is a distributer and a publisher of ebooks, magazines and music.

- Support a content service http://imobilco.ru using HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap+LESS, Javascript, BackboneJS, lodash.js, handlebars.js.
- Refactored front-end building system using NodeJS, Grunt, Yeoman.
- Developed client proxy for front-end developers with partial loading server side HTML and client side JS, CSS and images.
- Integrated Google Analytics eCommerce API, that turned over service auditory valuation

## WeHeartPics

02 / 2013 - 04 / 2014

Senior Front-end developer

We Heart Pics is the only fully-functional, photo-powered, social network. They enable people to communicate without relying on a mutual language or location.

- Developed Responsive Mobile-ready Single-page web applications with templating on client side.
- Developed responsive web application using HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap+LESS, SVG, HTML5 APIs (Canvas API, Geo API), Javascript, BackboneJS, lodash.js, handlebars.js

- Developed build system using NodeJS, Grunt, Imagemagick, UglifyJS, JSHint, CSSMin, HTMLMin, ImageMin, NodeSprite.
- Developed
- Rewrote Open GL ES 2.0 shaders from mobile app to flash AGAL shaders.
- Rewrote the shaders to Javascript Canvas shader programs working on Webworkers.
- Developed proxy server using NodeJS, PhantomJS that made possible Search bot to crawl the dynamic ajax sites.
- Used Microformats and SEO best practices for photos, products.
- Used oEmbed for videos.
- Fixed existing markup according W3C stardards.

#### BigBuzzy.ru

11 / 2011 - 01 / 2013

Front-end developer

BigBuzzy is a Groupon-like service.

- Got a massive expertise in HTML pixel perfect layout.
- Applied Mobile-first and Progress Enhancement principles.
- Developed progress-enhancement-based mobile version of http://bigbuzzy.ru http://bigbuzzy.ru/m/ using modernizer.js, jQuery, lodash.js, CSS3, MediaQueries.
- Researched and rewrote best parts of jQueryMobile on the mobile site.
- Tested the mobile site and made all usecases feasible on a wide row of mobile operation systems (Nokia Symbian, Windows Phone, Android 1.6-3.0, IOS)
- Created Freemarker(FTL) templates kit of block macros, layout macros, functions and utilities.
- Rewrote templates from XSLT to Freemarker reaching best performance on new Java architecture
- Developed layout builder for email newsletters with that horrible HTML4
- Fixed existing markup according W3C stardards.

#### **SM & Partners**

12 / 2008 - 11 / 2011

Senior Front-end Developer

SM & Partners is a development company. Creation and Accompaniment high-load web projects like business-oriented social networking services, dating and hr networking services.

- Developed RPG in-browser game for kids using Javascript, jQuery, CSS, Flash, PHP, MySQL.
- Created and debugged internet browser based on Firefox with a parental control extension on XUL.
- Architected a server software using Python and Blender3D for fast prerendering and rendering animations of game characters.
- Developed service for accounting game character outfits and animations with PSD parsing, management of artist's works, and XML configs generation using Javascript, jQuery, psd.js, NodeJS, PHP, MySQL, imagemagick
- Used to be an instant scrum master in front-end team of 5 members.
- Developed the video coder software based on FFMPEG and PHP on serverside as part of blogs social network http://f5.ru

#### Mediatoday

03 / 2008 - 12 / 2008

Web Developer

Mediatoday is a full-service digital agency

• Developed and supported a full imdb-like service with online reservation eticket with PHP,

Mys

- Developed front-end part of the service using HTML4, CSS, Javascript, jQuery and Flash plus Papervision3d for the eticket reservation module.
- Developed PHP bot synchronizing schedules and reservations from each connected cinema.

#### BellIntegrator

10 / 2005 - 03 / 2008

Web Developer

Bell Integrator is a global consulting, technology services, and outsourcing company that offers business critical solutions that resolve your most complex IT and business needs for top-tier telecom, finance, transportation, and healthcare enterprises.

- Developed the graphic charts modules (plain tree chart with the backpack algorithm and other trees, pies, bars etc.) for monitoring systems.
- Got a huge experience in Javascript, Actionscript and enterprise development.
- Utilized tricks for aggregating and displaying really big data on really slow client's computers.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **Vyatka State Technical University**

2000 - 2005

Master's Degree, Computer Science

## **INTERESTS**

Entrepreneurship, GFX, New Technologies

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

#### Developing Innovative Ideas for New Companies: The First Step in Entrepreneurship

04 / 2014

Coursera

## **Google Analytics Platform Principles**

03 / 2014

Google · License: fc7fe77b83034f0cb2ca4acd7f4d447b

Startup Engineering

09 / 2013

Coursera

#### MCTS Microsoft SQL Server

2007

# **LANGUAGES**

- English ( Professional working proficiency )
- Russian ( Native or bilingual proficiency )

## **PUBLICATIONS**

## 2.5D games and feature of multiplayer game development

10 / 2010

 $Highload + + \ Conference \ \cdot \ Authors: \ Gleb \ Polushkin \ \cdot \ \underline{http://www.slideshare.net/Gleb Polushkin/ss-5596094}$ 

It's my report for Highload++ Conference 2010 - a review of servers and client technologies plus frameworks for multiplayer browser games. There I presented SmartFox Server as the best solution for that time.

## Mobile Front-end development blog

http://blog.prolll.com/ · Authors: Gleb Polushkin · <a href="http://blog.prolll.com/">http://blog.prolll.com/</a> · Authors: Gleb Polushkin · <a href="http://blog.prolll.com/">http://blog.prolll.com/</a> ·

My blog in Russian is about Mobile Front-end development. Quite often I need to write down and share an unknown mobile browser feature so this blog is designed for this.